<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37724240</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dengue Infection Triggering Concurrent Thrombotic Thrombocytopenic Purpura in a Case of Chronic Idiopathic Thrombocytopenic Purpura.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e43684</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e43684</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e43684</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.43684</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We present a case report detailing the medical history of a 53-year-old female who had a well-established 10-year history of idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP). The patient presented with fever and gum bleeding, prompting a series of laboratory investigations. These examinations revealed concurrent thrombocytopenia and hemolytic anemia, alongside a positive test result for serum dengue IgM antibodies. Initial treatment for the patient involved intravenous administration of glucocorticoids and intravenous immunoglobulin. Regrettably, this therapeutic intervention did not yield a favorable response. Subsequent clinical developments, including the onset of generalized tonic-clonic seizures, raised suspicions of thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP). A notable diagnostic indicator was the elevated PLASMIC score (platelet count; combined hemolysis variable; absence of active cancer; absence of stem-cell or solid-organ transplant; mean corpuscular volume; international normalized ratio; creatinine), reinforcing the consideration of TTP. To confirm the diagnosis, ADAMTS13 (a disintegrin and metalloproteinase with thrombospondin motifs 13) enzyme levels were assessed and found to be low. Consequently, the patient was diagnosed with TTP. Plasmapheresis was administered, resulting in a positive clinical response after two cycles. Notably, the patient experienced a resolution of thrombocytopenia and hemolytic anemia. Following successful treatment, the patient was discharged with a prescription for immunosuppressants. This case underscores the critical importance of including TTP as a potential differential diagnosis when encountering patients with chronic ITP. TTP is characterized by its acute and life-threatening nature, often deviating from the typical clinical presentation. The application of the PLASMIC score serves as a valuable tool in guiding decision-making processes when TTP is suspected.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Rana et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rana</LastName><ForeName>Akash</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Government Medical College &amp; Hospital, Chandigarh, Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahlawat</LastName><ForeName>Prashant</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Government Medical College &amp; Hospital, Chandigarh, Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Upadhyay</LastName><ForeName>Prateek</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Government Medical College &amp; Hospital, Chandigarh, Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Akshita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Government Medical College &amp; Hospital, Chandigarh, Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bansal</LastName><ForeName>Aman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Medicine, Government Medical College &amp; Hospital, Chandigarh, Chandigarh, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dengue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dengue virus infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">itp managment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombocytopenic purpura</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37724240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10505267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.43684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Standardization of terminology, definitions and outcome criteria in immune thrombocytopenic purpura of adults and children: report from an international working group. Rodeghiero F, Stasi R, Gernsheimer T, et al. Blood. 2009;113:2386&#x2013;2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19005182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis of immune thrombocytopenia. Audia S, Mah&#xe9;vas M, Samson M, Godeau B, Bonnotte B. Autoimmun Rev. 2017;16:620&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28428120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and laboratory diagnosis of TTP: an integrated approach. Chiasakul T, Cuker A. Hematology Am Soc Hematol Educ Program. 2018;2018:530&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6246034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30504354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines on the diagnosis and management of the thrombotic microangiopathic haemolytic anaemias. Allford SL, Hunt BJ, Rose P, Machin SJ. Br J Haematol. 2003;120:556&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12588343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura: a hematological emergency. Kessler CS, Khan BA, Lai-Miller K. J Emerg Med. 2012;43:538&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22445678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura in a case of dengue fever: a rare presentation. Gavali AS, Shelgaonkar J, Bartakke S. Indian J Crit Care Med. 2017;21:226&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5416791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28515608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The American Society of Hematology 2011 evidence-based practice guideline for immune thrombocytopenia. Neunert C, Lim W, Crowther M, Cohen A, Solberg L Jr, Crowther MA. Blood. 2011;117:4190&#x2013;4207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequential immune thrombocytopenia (ITP) and thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (TTP) in an elderly male patient with primary Sjogren&#x2019;s syndrome: when in doubt, use the PLASMIC score. Miller DD, Krenzer JA, Kenkre VP, Rose WN. Case Rep Med. 2021;2021:6869342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8651386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34887925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derivation and external validation of the PLASMIC score for rapid assessment of adults with thrombotic microangiopathies: a cohort study. Bendapudi PK, Hurwitz S, Fry A, et al. Lancet Haematol. 2017;4:0&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A fatal case of dengue-associated hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis and retroperitoneal hematoma in a patient with autoimmune hemolytic anemia. Chang CY. Cureus. 2021;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8196493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34131542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical updates in adult immune thrombocytopenia. Lambert MP, Gernsheimer TB. Blood. 2017;129:2829&#x2013;2835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5813736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current insight into thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Verbeke L, Delforge M, Dierickx D. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis. 2010;21:3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19851089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical features and prognosis of patients with thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura associated with systemic lupus erythematosus: a review of 25 cases. Li J, Jiang JJ, Wang CY, et al. Ital J Pediatr. 2019;45:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6489191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31036039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Joly BS, Coppo P, Veyradier A. Blood. 2017;129:2836&#x2013;2846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISTH guidelines for treatment of thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Zheng XL, Vesely SK, Cataland SR, et al. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18:2496&#x2013;2502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8091490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyclosporine or steroids as an adjunct to plasma exchange in the treatment of immune-mediated thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Cataland SR, Kourlas PJ, Yang S, et al. Blood Adv. 2017;1:2075&#x2013;2082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5728286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29296854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment and monitoring of patients with immune-mediated thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (iTTP): strategies to improve outcomes. [ Jun; 2023 ];Kucukyurt S, Eskazan AE. J Blood Med. 2020 11:319&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7532071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antithrombotic drug candidate ALX-0081 shows superior preclinical efficacy and safety compared with currently marketed antiplatelet drugs. Ulrichts H, Silence K, Schoolmeester A, et al. Blood. 2011;118:757&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caplacizumab treatment for acquired thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Scully M, Cataland SR, Peyvandi F, et al. N Engl J Med. 2019;380:335&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30625070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Recombinant ADAMTS13 for hereditary thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Asmis LM, Serra A, Krafft A, et al. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:2356&#x2013;2361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36546627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>