<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37730740</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Predictors of the post-COVID condition following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5839</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5839</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-023-41541-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Whereas the nature of the post-COVID condition following mild acute COVID-19 is increasingly well described in the literature, knowledge of its risk factors, and whether it can be predicted, remains limited. This study, conducted in Norway, uses individual-level register data from 214,667 SARS-CoV-2 infected individuals covering a range of demographic, socioeconomic factors, as well as cause-specific healthcare utilization in the years prior to infection to assess the risk of post-COVID complaints &#x2265;3 months after testing positive. We find that the risk of post-COVID was higher among individuals who prior to infection had been diagnosed with psychological (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.12, 95% CI 1.84-2.44), respiratory (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.03, 95% CI 1.78-2.32), or general and unspecified health problems (OR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.78, 95% CI 1.52-2.09). To assess the predictability of post-COVID after mild initial disease, we use machine learning methods and find that pre-infection characteristics, combined with information on the SARS-CoV-2 virus type and vaccine status, to a considerable extent (AUC&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.79, 95% CI 0.75-0.81) could predict the occurrence of post-COVID complaints in our sample.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reme</LastName><ForeName>B-A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1554-0996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cluster for Health Services Research, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway. Bjorn-Atle.Reme@fhi.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Management and Health Economics, University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway. Bjorn-Atle.Reme@fhi.no.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gjesvik</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cluster for Health Services Research, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section for Breast Cancer Screening, Cancer Registry of Norway, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magnusson</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4851-5794</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cluster for Health Services Research, Norwegian Institute of Public Health, Oslo, Norway.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology Unit, Orthopedics, Department of Clinical Sciences Lund, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37730740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-41541-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-023-41541-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Caspersen, I. H., Magnus, P. &amp; Trogstad, L. Excess risk and clusters of symptoms after COVID-19 in a large Norwegian cohort. Eur. J. Epidemiol. 37, 539&#x2013;548 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-022-00847-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35211871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8872922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund, L. et al. Post-acute effects of SARS-CoV-2 infection in individuals not requiring hospital admission: a Danish population-based cohort study. Lancet Infect. Dis. 21 1373&#x2013;1382 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson, K. et al. Healthcare use in 700 000 children and adolescents for six months after covid-19: before and after register based cohort study. Br. Med. J. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2021-066809 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian, A. et al. Symptoms and risk factors for long COVID in non-hospitalized adults. Nat. Med. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01909-w (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf8;rensen, A. I. V. et al. A nationwide questionnaire study of post-acute symptoms and health problems after SARS-CoV-2 infection in Denmark. Nat. Commun. 13, 4213 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-31897-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35864108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9302226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, E. et al. Long COVID burden and risk factors in 10 UK longitudinal studies and electronic health records. Nat. Commun. 13, 3528 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-30836-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9240035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledford, H. How common is long COVID? Why studies give different answers. Nature https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-022-01702-2 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soriano, J. B., Murthy, S., Marshall, J. C., Relan, P. &amp; Diaz, J. V. A clinical case definition of post-COVID-19 condition by a Delphi consensus. Lancet Infect. Dis. 22, e102&#x2013;e107 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(21)00703-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aiyegbusi, L. et al. Symptoms, complications and management of long COVID: a review. J. R. Soc. Med. 114, 014107682110328 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01410768211032850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez Leon, S. et al. More than 50 long-term effects of COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci. Rep. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-95565-8 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelen, M. et al. Characterising long COVID: a living systematic review. BMJ Glob. Health 6, e005427 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjgh-2021-005427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudre, C. et al. Attributes and predictors of long COVID. Nat. Med. 27, 626&#x2013;631 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-de-Las-Pe&#xf1;as, C. et al. Prevalence of Post-COVID-19 symptoms in hospitalized and non-hospitalized COVID-19 survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur. J. Intern. Med. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejim.2021.06.009 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet, M. et al. Incidence, co-occurrence, and evolution of long-COVID features: A 6-month retrospective cohort study of 273,618 survivors of COVID-19. PLoS Med. 18, e1003773 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34582441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8478214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taquet, M., Geddes, J., Husain, M., Luciano, S. &amp; Harrison, P. 6-month neurological and psychiatric outcomes in 236 379 survivors of COVID-19: a retrospective cohort study using electronic health records. Lancet Psychiatry https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00084-5 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cervia, C. et al. Immunoglobulin signature predicts risk of post-acute COVID-19 syndrome. Nat. Commun. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-27797-1 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slomski, A. Belief in having had COVID-19 linked with long COVID symptoms. JAMA 327, 26 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34982131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackett, J., Wainberg, M., Elkind, M. &amp; Freedberg, D. Potential long COVID-19 gastrointestinal symptoms 6 months after coronavirus infection are associated with mental health symptoms. Gastroenterology https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2021.10.040 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garjani, A., Middleton, R., Nicholas, R. &amp; Evangelou, N. Recovery from COVID-19 in Multiple Sclerosis: A Prospective and Longitudinal Cohort Study of the United Kingdom Multiple Sclerosis Register. Neurol. - Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflammation 9, e1118 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000001118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. et al. Associations of depression, anxiety, worry, perceived stress, and loneliness prior to infection with risk of post-COVID-19 conditions. JAMA psychiatry https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.2640 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerlind, E., Palstam, A., Sunnerhagen, K. &amp; Persson, H. C. Patterns and predictors of sick leave after Covid-19 and long Covid in a national Swedish cohort. BMC Public Health https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-021-11013-2 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin, M. et al. Post-COVID syndrome in non-hospitalised patients with COVID-19: a longitudinal prospective cohort study. Lancet Regional Health - Eur. 6, 100122 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Aly, Z., Bowe, B. &amp; Xie, Y. Long COVID after breakthrough SARS-CoV-2 infection. Nat. Med. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01840-0 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayoubkhani, D. et al. Trajectory of long covid symptoms after covid-19 vaccination: community based cohort study. BMJ 377, e069676 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2021-069676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunvoll, S. et al. Post-acute symptoms 3-15 months after COVID-19 among unvaccinated and vaccinated individuals with a breakthrough infection. Int. J. Infect. Dis. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2022.11.009 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skyrud, K., Telle, K. &amp; Magnusson, K. Impacts of mild and severe COVID-19 on sick leave. Int. J. Epidemiol. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyab182 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson, K., Turkiewicz, A., Flottorp, S. A. &amp; Englund, M. Prevalence of long COVID complaints in persons with and without COVID-19. Sci. Rep. 13, 6074 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-32636-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10100609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, J., Wong, A., Zhu, D., Fastenberg, J. &amp; Tham, T. The prevalence of olfactory and gustatory dysfunction in COVID-19 patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Otolaryngol. Head Neck Surgery https://doi.org/10.1177/0194599820926473 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massetti, G. et al. Summary of Guidance for Minimizing the Impact of COVID-19 on Individual Persons, Communities, and Health Care Systems &#x2014; United States, August 2022. Morb. Mortal. Weekly Rep. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.mm7133e1 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Directorate of E-health. Code guidance for COVID-19 https://www.ehelse.no/kodeverk-og-terminologi/ICPC-2/kodeveiledning-ved-covid-19 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flatby, A. V. H., Jan Peter William, Brurberg, Kjetil Gundro, Gravningen, Kirsten Midttun. COVID-19: Post COVID-19 condition &#x2013; a rapid review. (Norwegian Institute of Public Health, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnusson, K. et al. Post-covid medical complaints following infection with SARS-CoV-2 Omicron vs Delta variants. Nat. Commun. 13, 7363 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-35240-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36450749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9709355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katon, W., Lin, E. H. B. &amp; Kroenke, K. The association of depression and anxiety with medical symptom burden in patients with chronic medical illness. Gen. Hospital Psychiatry 29, 147&#x2013;155 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2006.11.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sporaland, G., Mouland, G., Bratland, B., Rygh, E. &amp; Reiso, H. Allmennlegers bruk av ICPC-diagnoser og samsvar med journalnotatene. Tidsskrift for Den norske legeforening https://doi.org/10.4045/tidsskr.18.0440 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>James, G., Witten, D., Hastie, T. &amp; Tibshirani, R. An Introduction to Statistical Learning, with Applications in R https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-0716-1418-1 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman, L. Random forests. Mach. Learn. 45, 5&#x2013;32 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1010933404324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong, E., DeLong, D. &amp; Clarke-Pearson, D. Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves: a nonparametric approach. Biometrics 44, 837&#x2013;845 (1988).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2531595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reme, B.-A., Gjesvik, J. &amp; Magnusson, K. Predictors of the post-COVID condition following mild SARS-CoV-2 infection https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/661041995 (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>