<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37730690</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Building a prediction model of college students' sports behavior based on machine learning method: combining the characteristics of sports learning interest and sports autonomy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15628</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15628</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-41496-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>College students' sports behavior is affected by many factors, and sports learning interest and sports autonomy support are potential psychological characteristic factors, which have important influence value on college students' sports behavior. Machine learning methods are widely used to construct prediction models and show high efficiency. In order to understand the impact of sports learning interest and sports autonomy support on college students' sports behavior (physical exercise level), the research decided to use the relevant methods of machine learning to build a prediction model, so as to find the internal relationship between them. This paper summarizes the relevant factors that affect college students' sports behavior (physical exercise level) from two aspects, namely, sports autonomy and sports learning interest, and surveys the demographic and sociological information of college students as a supplement. The research evaluates the level of the prediction model through the construction of the prediction model of the machine learning algorithm and the comparison method, so as to determine the optimal prediction model. The results show that the prediction accuracy of the logistic regression model is 0.7288, the recall rate is 0.7590, and F1 is 0.7397; The prediction accuracy of KNN model is 0.6895, the recall rate is 0.7596, and F1 is 0.7096; The prediction accuracy of naive Bayesian model is 0.7166, the recall rate is 0.6703, and F1 is 0.6864; the prediction accuracy of LDA model is 0.7263, the recall rate is 0.7290, and F1 is 0.7265; The prediction accuracy of the support vector machine model is 0.6563, the recall rate is 0.7700, and F1 is 0.6845; The prediction accuracy of GBDT model is 0.6953, the recall rate is 0.7039, and the F1 score is 0.6989; The prediction accuracy of the decision tree model is 0.6872, the recall rate is 0.6507, and F1 is 0.6672. The logistic regression model performs best in the combination of sports learning interest and motor autonomy support, due to the combination of its linear classification characteristics, better adaptability, high computational efficiency, and better adaptability to feature selection and outlier processing. The conclusion points out that the prediction level of logistic regression model is the highest when combining sports learning interest and sports autonomy support to predict college students' sports behavior (sports exercise grade), which also provides an important reference for improving college students' sports behavior (sports exercise grade).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Haibo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Faculty Department, Liaoning University, Shenyang, 110036, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Teaching Department of Shandong Jiaotong University (Weihai Campus), Weihai, 264209, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emolyn</LastName><ForeName>Iringan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. Paul University Philippines Graduate School Department, 3500, Tuguegarao, Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Faculty Department, Liaoning University, Shenyang, 110036, China. yuliu@lnu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37730690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-41496-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-41496-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gao, J. et al. Gait recognition and prediction research based on improved machine learning algorithms. J. Biomed. Eng. 001, 039 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. &amp; Qiu, W. Research progress on causal inference methods based on machine learning. Stat. Decis. 37(11), 10&#x2013;15 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T. et al. The impact of teaching methods, learning stress, and learning interest on high school students&#x2019; academic performance&#x2014;Based on a moderated mediation model. Educ. Sci. Res. 10, 63&#x2013;69 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, S. Research on intelligent prescription of college students' physical health based on machine learning. Doctoral dissertation, Xihua University (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Z. et al. How family structure influences middle school students&#x2019; participation in physical exercise and their academic performance. J. Humanit. Soc. Sci. Commun. 10(1), 1&#x2013;9 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz, W., Dayan, P. &amp; Montague, P. R. Neural substrates of prediction and reward. Science 275(5306), 1593&#x2013;1599 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.275.5306.1593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, L. Research on the linkage and countermeasures of college students&#x2019; physical health indicators based on Apriori algorithm. Fujian Sports Sci. Technol. 040(005), 24&#x2013;29 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bing, D. et al. Research on prognosis classification of sudden deafness based on deep learning methods. J. Clin. Otolaryngol. 32(15), 5 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, J., Yang, W. &amp; Chen, Q. Dimension identification of psychological test items based on statistical variable selection methods. Stat. Inf. Forum 31(11), 6 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouveia, E. R. et al. Physical fitness predicts subsequent improvement in academic achievement: Differential patterns depending on pupils&#x2019; age. Sustainability 12(21), 8874 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12218874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z. The influence of physical exercise on negative emotions of college students: The mediating role of self-efficacy and the mediating and moderating effects of psychological resilience. J. Sports Sci. 27(5), 7 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, R. et al. Mechanism of self-support on college students&#x2019; exercise persistence: A moderated mediation model. J. Beijing Sport Univ. https://doi.org/10.19582/j.cnki.11-3785/g8.2020.08.011 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19582/j.cnki.11-3785/g8.2020.08.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, J. &amp; Lin, J. Research on the influencing factors and mechanism of physical learning interest of primary and middle school students in China. J. Beijing Sport Univ. 11, 13 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louw, N. &amp; Steel, S. J. Variable selection in kernel Fisher discriminant analysis by means of recursive feature elimination. Comput. Stat. Data Anal. 51(3), 2043&#x2013;2055 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.csda.2005.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Q., Li, S., Li, Z., et al. Research on obstacle avoidance of mobile robots based on machine learning algorithms. Mech. Des. Manuf. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, W. et al. 3-month blood glucose prediction of type 2 diabetes patients based on machine learning algorithms. Chin. J. Dis. Control Prev. 23(11), 1313&#x2013;1317 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, X. et al. Comparison of multiple machine learning algorithms for iceberg identification based on Sentinel-1A data. Acta Geod. et Cartogr. Sin. 49(4), 509&#x2013;521 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L. et al. Prognostic prediction of primary liver cancer patients based on multi-class support vector machine recursive feature elimination method. Biomed. Eng. Res. 38(1), 5 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Z., Zhao, M. &amp; Hu, C. An effective dimensionality reduction feature selection method and its application in acoustic target recognition (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y., Li, M. &amp; Lv, J. A feature selection method based on chi-square test. Comput. Sci. 42(5), 4 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, Z. Research on Support Vector Machine Classification Method based on Principal Component Analysis and Recursive Feature Elimination (Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. &amp; Guo, Y. Application of improved XGBoost model in stock prediction. Comput. Eng. Appl. 55(20), 202&#x2013;207 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohajane, M. et al. Application of remote sensing and machine learning algorithms for forest fire mapping in a Mediterranean area. Ecol. Ind. 129, 107869 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2021.107869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, P., Liu, G., Wang, Z. &amp; Guards. A hierarchical classification model based on class unbalanced data. J. Univ. Sci. Technol. China 45(1) (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, J. Construction and platform development of skin injury care adverse event prediction model based on big data technology. Doctoral dissertation, Chinese PLA Medical Academy (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. S. C., Cui, H., Du, M. H., et al. Machine learning-based Guangcai porcelain pattern generation system. Front. Inf. Technol. Electron. Eng. (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, F. et al. Multi-objective evolutionary algorithm for optimizing the partial area under the ROC curve. Knowl.-Based Syst. 170(15), 69&#x2013;100 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan, G., Hassan, A., Diao, Q., et al. Improved nearest neighbor methods for text classification (Technical Report No. CSE-TR-576&#x2013;11). University of Michigan, Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, Y. Application and implementation of decision tree method in agricultural intelligent decision-making. Doctoral dissertation, China Agricultural University (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansour, Y. Pessimistic decision tree pruning based on tree size. In: Fourteenth International Conference on Machine Learning. Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc., pp. 195&#x2013;201 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Z. Research dynamics and progress on college students&#x2019; physical exercise behavior. J. Nanjing Inst. Phys. Educ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 12(01), 144&#x2013;148 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y., Guo, L., Chen, P. &amp; Xu, C. Model construction of peer relationships and adolescent sports motivation and engagement. J. Tianjin Univ. Sport 25(03), 218&#x2013;223 (2010).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>