<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37720780</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Finding Lead Compounds for Dengue Antivirals from a Collection of Old Drugs through <i>In Silico</i> Target Prediction and Subsequent <i>In Vitro</i> Validation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>32483</StartPage><EndPage>32497</EndPage><MedlinePgn>32483-32497</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.3c02607</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Dengue virus (DENV) infection is one of the most widely spread flavivirus infections. Despite the fatality it could cause, no antiviral treatment is currently available to treat the disease. Hence, this study aimed to repurpose old drugs as novel DENV NS3 inhibitors. Ligand-based (L-B) and proteochemometric (PCM) prediction models were built using 62,354 bioactivity data to screen for potential NS3 inhibitors. Selected drugs were then subjected to the foci forming unit reduction assay (FFURA) and protease inhibition assay. Finally, molecular docking was performed to validate these results. The <i>in silico</i> studies revealed that both models performed well in the internal and external validations. However, the L-B model showed better accuracy in the external validation in terms of its sensitivity (0.671). In the <i>in vitro</i> validation, all drugs (zileuton, trimethadione, and linalool) were able to moderately inhibit the viral activities at the highest concentration tested. Zileuton showed comparable results with linalool when tested at 2 mM against the DENV NS3 protease, with a reduction of protease activity at 17.89 and 18.42%, respectively. Two new compounds were also proposed through the combination of the selected drugs, which are ziltri (zilueton + trimethadione) and zilool (zileuton + linalool). The molecular docking study confirms the <i>in vitro</i> observations where all drugs and proposed compounds were able to achieve binding affinity &#x2265; -4.1 kcal/mol, with ziltri showing the highest affinity at -7.7 kcal/mol, surpassing the control, panduratin A. The occupation of both S1 and S2 subpockets of NS2B-NS3 may be essential and a reason for the lower binding energy shown by the proposed compounds compared to the screened drugs. Based on the results, this study provided five potential new lead compounds (ziltri, zilool, zileuton, linalool, and trimethadione) for DENV that could be modified further.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdullah</LastName><ForeName>Zafirah Liyana</ForeName><Initials>ZL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Life Sciences, Faculty of Pharmacy, Universiti Teknologi MARA Selangor, Puncak Alam Campus, 42300 Bandar Puncak Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chee</LastName><ForeName>Hui-Yee</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 UPM Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusof</LastName><ForeName>Rohana</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, 50603 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohd Fauzi</LastName><ForeName>Fazlin</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1572-9449</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, UiTM Selangor, Puncak Alam Campus, 42300 Bandar Puncak Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collaborative Drug Discovery Research, Faculty of Pharmacy, Universiti Teknologi MARA Selangor, Puncak Alam Campus, 42300 Bandar Puncak Alam, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37720780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10500654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c02607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health
Organization . Dengue and Severe
Dengue, 2018. http://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/dengue-and-severe-dengue. (accessed October 26, 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengue
Worldwide Overview, 2022. https://www.ecdc.europa.eu/en/dengue-monthly. (accessed July 06, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obi J. O.; Guti&#xe9;rrez-Barbosa H.; Chua J. V.; Deredge D. J. Current Trends and Limitations in Dengue Antiviral Research. Trop. Med. Infect. Dis. 2021, 6, 18010.3390/tropicalmed6040180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/tropicalmed6040180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8544673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34698303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>First FDA-approved vaccine for the prevention
of dengue disease in
endemic regions [Press release] U.S. Food and
Drug Administration. https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/first-fda-approved-vaccine-prevention-dengue-disease-endemic-regions (accessed July 27, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low J. G. H.; Ooi E. E.; Vasudevan S. G. Current Status of Dengue Therapeutics Research and Development. J. Infect. Dis. 2017, 215, S96&#x2013;S102. 10.1093/infdis/jiw423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiw423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28403438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu F.; Shi P.-Y. The Challenges of Dengue Drug Discovery and Development. Clin. Invest. 2014, 4, 683&#x2013;685. 10.4155/cli.14.67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4155/cli.14.67</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behnam M. A. M.; Nitsche C.; Boldescu V.; Klein C. D. The Medicinal Chemistry of Dengue Virus. J. Med. Chem. 2016, 59, 5622&#x2013;5649. 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.5b01653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.5b01653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26771861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira A. S.; da Silva M. L.; Oliveira A. F. C. S.; da Silva C. C.; Teixeira R. R.; De Paula S. O. NS3 and NS5 Proteins: Important Targets for Anti-Dengue Drug Design. J. Braz. Chem. Soc. 2014, 25, 1759&#x2013;1769. 10.5935/0103-5053.20140057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5935/0103-5053.20140057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson S. M.; Malmstrom R. D.; Russo A.; Mueller N.; Pang Y.-P.; Watowich S. J. Structure-Based Discovery of Dengue Virus Protease Inhibitors. Antiviral Res. 2009, 82, 110&#x2013;114. 10.1016/j.antiviral.2009.02.190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2009.02.190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2680748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19428601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin K.-H.; Nalivaika E. A.; Prachanronarong K. L.; Yilmaz N. K.; Schiffer C. A. Dengue Protease Substrate Recognition: Binding of the Prime Side. ACS Infect. Dis. 2016, 2, 734&#x2013;743. 10.1021/acsinfecdis.6b00131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsinfecdis.6b00131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5221572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27657335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman M. M.; Biswas S.; Islam K. J.; Paul A. S.; Mahato S. K.; Ali M. A.; Halim M. A. Antiviral Phytochemicals as Potent Inhibitors against NS3 Protease of Dengue Virus. Comput. Biol. Med. 2021, 134, 10449210.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiomed.2021.104492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakulin I.; Pasechnikov V.; Varlamicheva A.; Sannikova I. NS3 Protease Inhibitors for Treatment of Chronic Hepatitis C: Efficacy and Safety. World J. Hepatol. 2014, 6, 326&#x2013;339. 10.4254/wjh.v6.i5.326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4254/wjh.v6.i5.326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4033290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24868326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z.; Fang H.; Reagan K.; Xu X.; Mendrick D. L.; Slikker W.; Tong W. In Silico Drug Repositioning &#x2013; What We Need to Know. Drug Discovery Today 2013, 18, 110&#x2013;115. 10.1016/j.drudis.2012.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2012.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22935104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novick P. A.; Ortiz O. F.; Poelman J.; Abdulhay A. Y.; Pande V. S. SWEETLEAD: An in Silico Database of Approved Drugs, Regulated Chemicals, and Herbal Isolates for Computer-Aided Drug Discovery. PloS One 2013, 8 (11), e7956810.1371/journal.pone.0079568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0079568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3815155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24223973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wishart D. S.; Feunang Y. D.; Guo A. C.; Lo E. J.; Marcu A.; Grant J. R.; Sajed T.; Johnson D.; Li C.; Sayeeda Z.; Assempour N.; Iynkkaran I.; Liu Y.; Maciejewski A.; Gale N.; Wilson A.; Chin L.; Cummings R.; Le D.; Pon A.; Knox C.; Wilson M. DrugBank 5.0: A Major Update to the DrugBank Database for 2018. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018, 46, D1074&#x2013;D1082. 10.1093/nar/gkx1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkx1037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huchting J. Targeting Viral Genome Synthesis as Broad-Spectrum Approach against RNA Virus Infections. Antiviral Chem. Chemother. 2020, 28, 20402066209767810.1177/2040206620976786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2040206620976786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33297724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzenmeier G. Inhibition of the NS2B&#x2013;NS3 protease: towards a causative therapy for dengue virus diseases. Dengue Bull. 2004, 28, 58&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valle R. P. C.; Falgout B. Mutagenesis of the NS3 Protease of Dengue Virus Type 2. J. Virol. 1998, 72, 624&#x2013;632. 10.1128/JVI.72.1.624-632.1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.72.1.624-632.1998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC109416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9420267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussein H. A.; Borrel A.; Geneix C.; Petitjean M.; Regad L.; Camproux A.-C. PockDrug-Server: A New Web Server for Predicting Pocket Druggability on Holo and Apo Proteins. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015, 43, W436&#x2013;W442. 10.1093/nar/gkv462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkv462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25956651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman R.; Othman R.; Baharuddin A.; Ramakrishnan N. R.; Abd Rahman N.; Yusof R.; Karsani S. A. Molecular Docking Studies of Selected Medicinal Drugs as Dengue Virus-2 Protease Inhibitors. Sains Malays. 2017, 46, 1865&#x2013;1875. 10.17576/jsm-2017-4610-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17576/jsm-2017-4610-25</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiat T. S.; Pippen R.; Yusof R.; Ibrahim H.; Khalid N.; Rahman N. A. Inhibitory Activity of Cyclohexenyl Chalcone Derivatives and Flavonoids of Fingerroot, Boesenbergia Rotunda (L.), towards Dengue-2 Virus NS3 Protease. Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2006, 16, 3337&#x2013;3340. 10.1016/j.bmcl.2005.12.075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmcl.2005.12.075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapins M.; Worachartcheewan A.; Spjuth O.; Georgiev V.; Prachayasittikul V.; Nantasenamat C.; Wikberg J. E. S. A Unified Proteochemometric Model for Prediction of Inhibition of Cytochrome P450 Isoforms. PLoS One 2013, 8, e6656610.1371/journal.pone.0066566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0066566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3684587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23799117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niijima S.; Shiraishi A.; Okuno Y. Dissecting Kinase Profiling Data to Predict Activity and Understand Cross-Reactivity of Kinase Inhibitors. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2012, 52, 901&#x2013;912. 10.1021/ci200607f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci200607f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung D.; Schroder K.; White H.; Fang N. X.; Stoermer M. J.; Abbenante G.; Martin J. L.; Young P. R.; Fairlie D. P. Activity of Recombinant Dengue 2 Virus NS3 Protease in the Presence of a Truncated NS2B Co-Factor, Small Peptide Substrates, and Inhibitors. J. Biol. Chem. 2001, 276, 45762&#x2013;45771. 10.1074/jbc.M107360200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M107360200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holbeck S. L.; Collins J. M.; Doroshow J. H. Analysis of FDA-Approved Anti-Cancer Agents in the NCI60 Panel of Human Tumor Cell Lines. Mol. Cancer Ther. 2010, 9, 1451&#x2013;1460. 10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-10-0106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-10-0106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2868078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20442306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwivedi V. D.; Tripathi I. P.; Bharadwaj S.; Kaushik A. C.; Mishra S. K. Identification of New Potent Inhibitors of Dengue Virus NS3 Protease from Traditional Chinese Medicine Database. VirusDisease 2016, 27, 220&#x2013;225. 10.1007/s13337-016-0328-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13337-016-0328-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28466032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman R.; Kiat T. S.; Khalid N.; Yusof R.; Irene Newhouse E.; Newhouse J. S.; Alam M.; Rahman N. A. Docking of Noncompetitive Inhibitors into Dengue Virus Type 2 Protease: Understanding the Interactions with Allosteric Binding Sites. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2008, 48, 1582&#x2013;1591. 10.1021/ci700388k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci700388k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18656912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariono M.; Choi S. B.; Roslim R. F.; Nawi M. S.; Tan M. L.; Kamarulzaman E. E.; Mohamed N.; Yusof R.; Othman S.; Rahman N. A.; Othman R.; Wahab H. A. Thioguanine-Based DENV-2 NS2B/NS3 Protease Inhibitors: Virtual Screening, Synthesis, Biological Evaluation and Molecular Modelling. PLoS One 2019, 14, e021086910.1371/journal.pone.0210869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0210869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30677071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz B. A.; Elrod K.; Luong C.; Rice M. J.; Mackman R. L.; Sprengeler P. A.; Spencer J.; Hataye J.; Janc J.; Link J.; Litvak J.; Rai R.; Rice K.; Sideris S.; Verner E.; Young W. A Novel Serine Protease Inhibition Motif Involving a Multi-Centered Short Hydrogen Bonding Network at the Active Site. J. Mol. Biol. 2001, 307, 1451&#x2013;1486. 10.1006/jmbi.2001.4516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jmbi.2001.4516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11292354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidtke P.; Barril X. Understanding and Predicting Druggability. A High-Throughput Method for Detection of Drug Binding Sites. J. Med. Chem. 2010, 53, 5858&#x2013;5867. 10.1021/jm100574m.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jm100574m</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20684613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaulton A.; Hersey A.; Nowotka M.; Bento A. P.; Chambers J.; Mendez D.; Mutowo P.; Atkinson F.; Bellis L. J.; Cibri&#xe1;n-Uhalte E.; Davies M.; Dedman N.; Karlsson A.; Magari&#xf1;os M. P.; Overington J. P.; Papadatos G.; Smit I.; Leach A. R. The ChEMBL Database in 2017. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017, 45, D945&#x2013;D954. 10.1093/nar/gkw1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkw1074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5210557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S.; Chen J.; Cheng T.; Gindulyte A.; He J.; He S.; Li Q.; Shoemaker B. A.; Thiessen P. A.; Yu B.; Zaslavsky L.; Zhang J.; Bolton E. E. PubChem 2019 Update: Improved Access to Chemical Data. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019, 47, D1102&#x2013;D1109. 10.1093/nar/gky1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gky1033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T.; Lin Y.; Wen X.; Jorissen R. N.; Gilson M. K. BindingDB: A Web-Accessible Database of Experimentally Determined Protein-Ligand Binding Affinities. Nucleic Acids Res. 2007, 35, D198&#x2013;D201. 10.1093/nar/gkl999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkl999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1751547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UniProt: A Worldwide Hub of Protein Knowledge. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019, 47, D506&#x2013;D515. 10.1093/nar/gky1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gky1049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers D.; Hahn M. Extended-Connectivity Fingerprints. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2010, 50, 742&#x2013;754. 10.1021/ci100050t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci100050t</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20426451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bender A. How Similar Are Those Molecules after All? Use Two Descriptors and You Will Have Three Different Answers. Expert Opin. Drug Discovery 2010, 5, 1141&#x2013;1151. 10.1517/17460441.2010.517832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17460441.2010.517832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22822717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parzen E. On Estimation of a Probability Density Function and Mode. Ann. Math. Stat. 1962, 33, 1065&#x2013;1076. 10.1214/aoms/1177704472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1214/aoms/1177704472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblatt M. Remarks on Some Nonparametric Estimates of a Density Function. Ann. Math. Stat. 1956, 27, 832&#x2013;837. 10.1214/aoms/1177728190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1214/aoms/1177728190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aitchison J.; Aitken C. G. G. Multivariate Binary Discrimination by the Kernel Method. Biometrika 1976, 63, 413&#x2013;420. 10.1093/biomet/63.3.413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/biomet/63.3.413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgar R. C. MUSCLE: Multiple Sequence Alignment with High Accuracy and High Throughput. Nucleic Acids Res. 2004, 32, 1792&#x2013;1797. 10.1093/nar/gkh340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkh340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC390337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant B. J.; Rodrigues A. P. C.; ElSawy K. M.; McCammon J. A.; Caves L. S. D. Bio3d: An R Package for the Comparative Analysis of Protein Structures. Bioinformatics 2006, 22, 2695&#x2013;2696. 10.1093/bioinformatics/btl461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btl461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathea M.; Klingspohn W.; Baumann K. Chemoinformatic Classification Methods and Their Applicability Domain. Mol. Inf. 2016, 35, 160&#x2013;180. 10.1002/minf.201501019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/minf.201501019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27492083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afantitis A.; Melagraki G.; Sarimveis H.; Koutentis P. A.; Markopoulos J.; Igglessi-Markopoulou O. Development and Evaluation of a QSPR Model for the Prediction of Diamagnetic Susceptibility. QSAR Comb. Sci. 2008, 27, 432&#x2013;436. 10.1002/qsar.200730083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qsar.200730083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melagraki G.; Afantitis A.; Sarimveis H.; Koutentis P. A.; Kollias G.; Igglessi-Markopoulou O. Predictive QSAR Workflow for the in Silico Identification and Screening of Novel HDAC Inhibitors. Mol. Diversity 2009, 13, 301&#x2013;311. 10.1007/s11030-009-9115-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11030-009-9115-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19205914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthold M. R.; Cebron N.; Dill F.; Gabriel T. R.; K&#xf6;tter T.; Meinl T.; Ohl P.; Sieb C.; Thiel K.; Wiswedel B.. KNIME: The Konstanz Information Miner. In Data Analysis, Machine Learning, and Applications; Preisach C.; Burkhardt H.; Schmidt-Thieme L.; Decker R., Eds.; Springer: Berlin Heidelberg, 2008; pp 319&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandi K.; Teoh B.-T.; Sam S.-S.; Wong P.-F.; Mustafa M. R.; AbuBakar S. Novel Antiviral Activity of Baicalein against Dengue Virus. BMC Complementary Altern. Med. 2012, 12, 21410.1186/1472-6882-12-214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6882-12-214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3528482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23140177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothan H. A.; Abdulrahman A. Y.; Sasikumer P. G.; Othman S.; Abd Rahman N.; Yusof R. Protegrin-1 Inhibits Dengue NS2B-NS3 Serine Protease and Viral Replication in MK2 Cells. J. Biomed. Biotechnol. 2012, 2012, 1&#x2013;6. 10.1155/2012/251482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/251482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3470887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23093838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The PyMOL Molecular Graphics System, Version 2.0; Schr&#xf6;dinger, LLC, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vald&#xe9;s-Tresanco M. S.; Vald&#xe9;s-Tresanco M. E.; Valiente P. A.; Moreno E. AMDock: A Versatile Graphical Tool for Assisting Molecular Docking with Autodock Vina and Autodock4. Biol. Direct 2020, 15, 1210.1186/s13062-020-00267-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13062-020-00267-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7493944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolinsky T. J.; Nielsen J. E.; McCammon J. A.; Baker N. A. PDB2PQR: An Automated Pipeline for the Setup of Poisson&#x2013;Boltzmann Electrostatics Calculations. Nucleic Acids Res. 2004, 32, W665&#x2013;W667. 10.1093/nar/gkh381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkh381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC441519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15215472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott O.; Olson A. J. AutoDock Vina: Improving the Speed and Accuracy of Docking with a New Scoring Function, Efficient Optimization, and Multithreading. J. Comput. Chem. 2010, 31, 455&#x2013;461. 10.1002/jcc.21334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.21334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19499576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Discovery Studio Visualizer, v21.1.0.20298; Biovia, Dassault Systemes: San Diego, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia W. M. N.; de Andrade F. D. C. P.; Filgueiras L. A.; Mendes A. N.; Assun&#xe7;&#xe3;o A. F. C.; Rodrigues N. D. S.; Marques R. B.; Filho A. L. M. L.; de Sousa D. P.; Da Silva Lopes L. Antidepressant Activity of Rose Oxide Essential Oil: Possible Involvement of Serotonergic Transmission. Heliyon 2021, 7, e0662010.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e06620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2021.e06620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8080052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33948502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siramshetty V. B; Grishagin I.; Nguyen &#x110;a.-T.; Peryea T.; Skovpen Y.; Stroganov O.; Katzel D.; Sheils T.; Jadhav A.; Mathe E. A; Southall N. T NCATS Inxight Drugs: A Comprehensive and Curated Portal for Translational Research. Nucleic Acids Res. 2022, 50 (D1), D1307&#x2013;D1316. 10.1093/nar/gkab918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkab918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8728186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34648031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavan S.; Rajendar S. Stereoselective Total Synthesis of (&#x2212;)-Nupharamine Utilizing an &#x3b1;-Chlorosulfide and a Sulfinimine for C&#x2013;C Bond Formation. Org. Biomol. Chem. 2016, 14, 131&#x2013;137. 10.1039/C5OB01750E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5OB01750E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26490750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Chemical Society . Diaboline, 2022. https://www.acs.org/content/acs/en/molecule-of-the-week/archive/d/diaboline.html. (accessed July 26, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo E. B.; Marcu J.. Cannabis Pharmacology: The Usual Suspects and a Few Promising Leads. In Cannabinoid Pharmacology; Kendall D.; Alexander S. P. H., Eds.; Academic Press, 2017; Vol. 8, pp 67&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28826544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>