<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37730651</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2040-2392</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecular autism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mol Autism</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Increased rates of chronic physical health conditions across all organ systems in autistic adolescents and adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35</StartPage><MedlinePgn>35</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13229-023-00565-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The poorer physical health of autistic adults compared to non-autistic adults has been highlighted by several epidemiological studies. However, research has so far been limited to specific geographical areas and has primarily focused on young autistic individuals (aged 35&#xa0;years and younger). Recent studies indicate a higher rate of mortality in autistic people, as well as poorer quality of self-reported healthcare interactions. This study aims to determine, first, whether autistic people experience greater levels of non-communicable health conditions and second, whether these are explained by differences in demographics (i.e. sex, country of residence, ethnicity, education level), alcohol use, smoking, body mass index (BMI), or family history of medical conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">We employed a cross-sectional, convenience-sampling study via an anonymous, online survey of autistic and non-autistic adults (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2305, mean age&#x2009;=&#x2009;41.6, 65.9% female, 49% autistic). The survey asked participants to self-report information about their demographics, autism diagnosis, diet, exercise, sleep, sexual health, substance use, personal medical history, and family medical history (for all first-degree, biological relatives). Binomial logistic regression across four iterative models of increasing complexity was applied to assess rates of physical health conditions. The Benjamini-Hochberg correction was used to account for multiple testing, and only physical health conditions that achieved at least 1% endorsement within the overall sample (n&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;22) were included in the analysis to reduce risk of Type I errors. We also used novel network analysis methods to test whether there are increased levels of multimorbidity between autistic and non-autistic people.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were significantly elevated rates of non-communicable conditions across all organ systems in autistic people, including gastrointestinal, neurological, endocrine, visual, ear/nose/throat, skin, liver and kidney, and haematological conditions. We confirmed previous findings by showing highly significant differences in rates of neurological and gastrointestinal symptoms (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001). In addition, we established in the largest sample to date that Ehler-Danlos Syndrome (EDS) was more likely to occur among autistic females compared to non-autistic females. Finally, we found a higher prevalence of Coeliac's disease among autistic individuals compared to non-autistic individuals after controlling for sex,&#xa0;ethnicity,&#xa0;country of residence, alcohol use, smoking, and BMI, but&#xa0;these results became non-significant after accounting for family history.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study is biased towards females, white individuals, highly educated people, and UK residents, likely due to sampling biases. Our self-report study design may also exclude those who lack access to computers, or those with intellectual disability. Our network analysis is also limited in size.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides evidence of widespread, physical health comorbidity that spans nearly all major organ systems in autistic adults compared to non-autistic adults, using both binary logistic regression and network models. Healthcare professionals must be made aware of the range of co-occurring physical health conditions that may be more common among autistic people. However, our findings also point towards potential avenues requiring further exploration, such as the association of autism with both Coeliac's disease and EDS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ward</LastName><ForeName>John H</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9108-7900</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Royal Devon University NHS Foundation Trust, Exeter, Devon, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Exeter Medical School, Devon, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Oxford, Department of Psychiatry, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Health NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Weir</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5434-9193</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism Research Centre, Department of Psychiatry, University of Cambridge, Douglas House, 18b Trumpington Road, CB2 8AH, Cambridge, UK. emw60@cam.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allison</LastName><ForeName>Carrie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2272-2090</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism Research Centre, Department of Psychiatry, University of Cambridge, Douglas House, 18b Trumpington Road, CB2 8AH, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baron-Cohen</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9217-2544</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism Research Centre, Department of Psychiatry, University of Cambridge, Douglas House, 18b Trumpington Road, CB2 8AH, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>214322\Z\18\Z</GrantID><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Mol Autism</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101534222</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ehlers-Danlos syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheumatological condition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37730651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13229-023-00565-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13229-023-00565-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Autism Prevalence Higher, According to Data from 11 ADDM Communities | CDC Online Newsroom | CDC. Accessed 19 Apr 2023 from https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2023/p0323-autism.html .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirvikoski T, Mittendorfer-Rutz E, Boman M, Larsson H, Lichtenstein P, B&#xf6;lte S. Premature mortality in autism spectrum disorder. Br J Psychiatry. 2016;208:232&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26541693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.114.160192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillberg C, Billstedt E, Sundh V, Gillberg IC. Mortality in autism: a prospective longitudinal community-based study. J Autism Dev Disord. 2009. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-009-0883-4 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-009-0883-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19148741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang YI, et al. Mortality and cause of death of Australians on the autism spectrum. Autism Res. 2019;12:806&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30802364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.2086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GS, Fleming M, Kinnear D, Henderson A, Pell JP, Melville C, Cooper SA. Mortality in 787,666 school pupils with and without autism: a cohort study. Autism. 2021;25:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32830516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361320944037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Lai MC, Balogh R, Chung H, Durbin A, Jachyra P, Tint A, Weiss J, Lin E. Premature mortality in a population-based cohort of autistic adults in Canada. Autism Res. 2022;15:1550&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.2741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jokiranta-Olkoniemi E, Gyllenberg D, Sucksdorff D, Suominen A, Kronstr&#xf6;m K, Chudal R, Sourander A. Risk for premature mortality and intentional self-harm in autism spectrum disorders. J Autism Dev Disord. 2021;51:3098&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-020-04768-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lunsky Y, Lai M-C, Balogh R, Chung H, Durbin A, et al. Premature mortality in a population-based cohort of autistic adults in Canada. Autism Res. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1002/AUR.2741 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/AUR.2741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohane IS, McMurry A, Weber G, et al. The co-morbidity burden of children and young adults with autism spectrum disorders. PLoS ONE. 2012. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0033224 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0033224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23239965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3515554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop-Fitzpatrick L, Movaghar A, Greenberg JS, Page D, DaWalt LS, Brilliant MH, Mailick MR. Using machine learning to identify patterns of lifetime health problems in decedents with autism spectrum disorder. Autism Res. 2018;11:1120&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6203659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.1960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croen LA, Zerbo O, Qian Y, Massolo ML, Rich S, Sidney S, Kripke C. The health status of adults on the autism spectrum. Autism. 2015;19:814&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25911091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361315577517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand BN, Angell AM, Harris L, Carpenter LA. Prevalence of physical and mental health conditions in Medicare-enrolled, autistic older adults. Autism. 2020;24:755&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31773968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361319890793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell PS, Pazol K, Wiggins LD, et al. Health status and health care use among adolescents identified with and without autism in early childhood &#x2014; Four U.S. sites, 2018&#x2013;2020. MMWR Recommen Rep. 2021;70:605&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydzewska E, Fleming M, Mackay D, Young-Southward G, Blacher J, Ross Bolourian Y, Widaman K, Cooper SA. General health status of youth with autism with and without intellectual disabilities transitioning from special education, and its relationship to personal and family circumstances: longitudinal cohort study. Int J Dev Disabil. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1080/20473869.2021.19666000 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20473869.2021.19666000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37346258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10281398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rydzewska E, Hughes-Mccormack LA, Gillberg C, Henderson A, Macintyre C, Rintoul J, Cooper SA. Prevalence of long-term health conditions in adults with autism: observational study of a whole country population. BMJ Open. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2018-023945 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-023945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30173164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6120653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortuna RJ, Robinson L, Smith TH, Meccarello J, Bullen B, Nobis K, Davidson PW. Health conditions and functional status in adults with autism: a cross-sectional evaluation. J Gen Intern Med. 2016;31:77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-015-3509-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miot S, Chancel R, Peries M, et al. Multimorbidity patterns and subgroups among autistic adults with intellectual disability: results from the EFAAR study. Autism. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1177/13623613221121623 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13623613221121623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36056616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;dgaard EM, Jensen K, Miskowiak KW, Mottron L. Autism comorbidities show elevated female-to-male odds ratios and are associated with the age of first autism diagnosis. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2021;144:475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34228813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9292172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.13345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin S, Costley D. The experiences and needs of female adults with high-functioning autism spectrum disorder. Autism. 2016;20:483&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26111537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361315590805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davignon MN, Qian Y, Massolo M, Croen LA. Psychiatric and medical conditions in transition-aged individuals with ASD. Pediatrics. 2018;141:S335&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29610415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2016-4300K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tick B, Bolton P, Happ&#xe9; F, Rutter M, Rijsdijk F. Heritability of autism spectrum disorders: a meta-analysis of twin studies. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2016;57:585&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26709141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpp.12499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpe RA, Curry W, Brown R, Shankar R. A public health approach to reducing health inequalities among adults with autism. Br J Gen Pract. 2019;69:534&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6808592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/bjgp19X706133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir E, Allison C, Baron-Cohen S. Autistic adults have poorer quality healthcare and worse health based on self-report data. Mol Autism. 2022;13:1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13229-022-00501-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, Neilson S, O&#x2019;Sullivan J, Carravallah L, Johnson M, Cullen W, Shaw SCK. Barriers to healthcare and self-reported adverse outcomes for autistic adults: a cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2022;12:e056904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35193921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8883251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-056904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason D, Ingham B, Birtles H, et al. How to improve healthcare for autistic people: a qualitative study of the views of autistic people and clinicians. Autism. 2021;25:774&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361321993709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oakley B, Tillmann J, Ruigrok A, et al. COVID-19 health and social care access for autistic people: European policy review. BMJ Open. 2021;11:e045341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34001500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8130751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-045341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Featherstone C, Sharpe RA, Axford N, Asthana S, Husk K. Health and wellbeing outcomes and social prescribing pathways in community-based support for autistic adults: a systematic mapping review of reviews. Health Soc Care Commun. 2022;30:e621&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hsc.13635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmot M, Bell R. Social determinants and non-communicable diseases: time for integrated action. BMJ. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1136/BMJ.L251 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/BMJ.L251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31653611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6526681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orsmond GI, Shattuck PT, Cooper BP, Sterzing PR, Anderson KA. Social participation among young adults with an autism spectrum disorder. J Autism Dev Disord. 2013;43:2710&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23615687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3795788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-013-1833-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rumball F, Happ&#xe9; F, Grey N. Experience of trauma and PTSD symptoms in autistic adults: risk of PTSD development following DSM-5 and non-DSM-5 traumatic life events. Autism Res. 2020;13:2122&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32319731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.2306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir E, Allison C, Warrier V, Baron-Cohen S. Increased prevalence of non-communicable physical health conditions among autistic adults. Autism. 2021;25:681&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361320953652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. J Roy Stat Soc Ser B. 1995;57:289&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall A, Altman DG, Holder RL, Royston P. Combining estimates of interest in prognostic modelling studies after multiple imputation: current practice and guidelines. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2009;9:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19638200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2727536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-9-57</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Borkulo CD, Borsboom D, Epskamp S, Blanken TF, Boschloo L, Schoevers RA. Waldorp LJ (2014) A new method for constructing networks from binary data. Sci Rep. 2014;4:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epskamp S, Borsboom D, Fried EI. Estimating psychological networks and their accuracy: a tutorial paper. Behav Res Methods. 2018;50:195&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/s13428-017-0862-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borkulo CV, et al. Comparing network structures on three aspects: a permutation test. Psychol Methods. 2017. https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.29455.38569 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13140/RG.2.2.29455.38569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casanova EL, Baeza-Velasco C, Buchanan CB, Casanova MF. The relationship between autism and ehlers-danlos syndromes, hypermobility spectrum disorders. J Pers Med. 2020;260(10):260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jpm10040260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop-Fitzpatrick L, Mazefsky CA, Eack SM, Minshew NJ. Correlates of social functioning in autism spectrum disorder: the role of social cognition. Res Autism Spectr Disord. 2017;35:25&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28839456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rasd.2016.11.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tint A, Brown HK, Chen S, Lai MC, Tarasoff LA, Vigod SN, Parish S, Havercamp SM, Lunsky Y. Health characteristics of reproductive-aged autistic women in Ontario: a population-based, cross-sectional study. Autism. 2021;25:1114&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8089036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361320982819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss JA, Isaacs B, Diepstra H, Wilton AS, Brown HK, McGarry C, Lunsky Y. Health concerns and health service utilization in a population cohort of young adults with autism spectrum disorder. J Autism Dev Disord. 2018;48:36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28900771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-017-3292-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deswal R, Narwal V, Dang A, Pundir CS. The prevalence of polycystic ovary syndrome: a brief systematic review. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2020;13:261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33627974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7879843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jhrs.JHRS_95_18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina-Perucha L, Pistillo A, Ravent&#xf3;s B, et al. Endometriosis prevalence and incidence trends in a large population-based study in Catalonia (Spain) from 2009 to 2018. Women&#x2019;s Health. 2022;18:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penzol MJ, Salazar De Pablo G, Llorente C, Moreno C, Hern&#xe1;ndez P, Dorado ML, Parellada M. Functional gastrointestinal disease in autism spectrum disorder: a retrospective descriptive study in a clinical sample. Front Psychiatry. 2019;10:179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31024351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6469513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemczyk J, Wagner C, von Gontard A. Incontinence in autism spectrum disorder: a systematic review. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2018;27:1523&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29019014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-017-1062-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ames JL, Mahajan A, Davignon MN, Massolo ML, Croen LA. Opportunities for inclusion and engagement in the transition of autistic youth from pediatric to adult healthcare: a qualitative study. J Autism Dev Disord. 2023;53:1850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35262827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-022-05476-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams LM, Turk DC. Psychosocial factors and central sensitivity syndromes. Curr Rheumatol Rev. 2015;11:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4728142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1573397111666150619095330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Boer C, Dries L, Terluin B, van der Wouden JC, Blankenstein AH, van Wilgen CP, Lucassen P, van der Horst HE. Central sensitization in chronic pain and medically unexplained symptom research: a systematic review of definitions, operationalizations and measurement instruments. J Psychosom Res. 2019;117:32&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2018.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant S, Norton S, Weiland RF, Scheeren AM, Begeer S. Hoekstra RA (2022) Autism and chronic ill health: an observational study of symptoms and diagnoses of central sensitivity syndromes in autistic adults. Mol Autism. 2022;13:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13229-022-00486-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunson JC, Agresta TP, Laubenbacher RC. Sensitivity of comorbidity network analysis. JAMIA Open. 2020;3:94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamiaopen/ooz067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringmann LF, Elmer T, Epskamp S, Krause RW, Schoch D, Wichers M, Wigman JTW, Snippe E. What do centrality measures measure in psychological networks? J Abnorm Psychol. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1037/abn0000446 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/abn0000446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bringmann LF, Albers C, Bockting C, et al. Psychopathological networks: theory, methods and practice. Behav Res Ther. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brat.2021.104011 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2021.104011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34998034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun JJ, Perera B, Henley W, et al. Epilepsy related multimorbidity, polypharmacy and risks in adults with intellectual disabilities: a national study. J Neurol. 2022;269:2750&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35067759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10938-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins LV, et al. A review of the pharmacotherapeutic considerations for managing epilepsy in people with autism. Expert Opinion Pharmacother. 2022;23:841&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2022.2055461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiet C, Gourfinkel-An I, Bouzamondo A, Tordjman S, Baulac M, Lechat P, Mottron L, Cohen D. Epilepsy in autism is associated with intellectual disability and gender: evidence from a meta-analysis. Biol Psychiatry. 2008;64:577&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2008.04.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Sun X, Sun C, Zou M, Chen Y, Huang J, Wu L, Chen WX. Prevalence of epilepsy in autism spectrum disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Autism. 2022;26:33&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13623613211045029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M, Krishnamurthy J, Susi A, Sullivan C, Gorman GH, Hisle-Gorman E, Erdie-Lalena CR, Nylund CM. Association of autism spectrum disorders and inflammatory bowel disease. J Autism Dev Disord. 2018;48:1523&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10803-017-3409-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayilara OF, Zhang L, Sajobi TT, Sawatzky R, Bohm E, Lix LM. Impact of missing data on bias and precision when estimating change in patient-reported outcomes from a clinical registry. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1186/S12955-019-1181-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/S12955-019-1181-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6604189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicano E, Dinsmore A, Charman T. Views on researcher-community engagement in autism research in the United Kingdom: a mixed-methods study. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e109946&#x2013;e109946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4193852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0109946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche L, Adams D, Clark M. Research priorities of the autism community: a systematic review of key stakeholder perspectives. Autism. 2020;25:336&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361320967790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cull WL, O&#x2019;Connor KG, Sharp S, Tang SFS. Response rates and response bias for 50 surveys of pediatricians. Health Serv Res. 2005;40:213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1361134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-6773.2005.00350.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aerny-Perreten N, Dom&#xed;nguez-Berj&#xf5;n MF, Esteban-Vasallo MD, Garc&#xed;a-Riolobos C. Participation and factors associated with late or non-response to an online survey in primary care. J Eval Clin Pract. 2015;21:688&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25929295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.12367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maenner MJ, Shaw KA, Bakian AV, et al. Prevalence and characteristics of autism spectrum disorder among children aged 8 years &#x2014; autism and developmental disabilities monitoring network, 11 sites, United States, 2018. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2021;70:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34855727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8639027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.ss7011a1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson E, Hatton C, Baines S, Robertson J. The physical health of British adults with intellectual disability: cross sectional study. Int J Equity Health. 2016;15:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-016-0296-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volk RJ, Mendoza TR, Hoover DS, Nishi SPE, Choi NJ, Bevers TB. Reliability of self-reported smoking history and its implications for lung cancer screening. Prev Med Rep. 2020;17:101037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31934536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6951268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmedr.2019.101037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell AJ, Bird V, Rizzo M, Hussain S, Meader N. Accuracy of one or two simple questions to identify alcohol-use disorder in primary care: a meta-analysis. Br J Gen Pract. 2014;64:e408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24982493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4073726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/bjgp14X680497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood JFG, DelPozo-Banos M, Frizzati A, Rai D, John A, Hall J. Neurological and psychiatric disorders among autistic adults: a population healthcare record study. Psychol Med. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291722002884 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291722002884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36189783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10482712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths S, Allison C, Kenny R, Holt R, Smith P, Baron-Cohen S. The vulnerability experiences quotient (VEQ): a study of vulnerability, mental health and life satisfaction in autistic adults. Autism Res. 2019;12:1516&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31274233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6851759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aur.2162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long S, Zhou H, Li S, Wang T, Ma Y, Li C, Zhou Y, Zhou S, Wu B, Wang Y. The clinical and genetic features of co-occurring epilepsy and autism spectrum disorder in Chinese Children. Front Neurol. 2019;10:505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31139143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6527735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2019.00505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell DB, Buie TM, Winter H, Bauman M, Sutcliffe JS, Perrin JM, Levitt P. Distinct genetic risk based on association of MET in families with co-occurring autism and gastrointestinal conditions. Pediatrics. 2009;123:1018&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2008-0819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calleja S, Islam FMA, Kingsley J, McDonald R. Healthcare access for autistic adults: a systematic review. Medicine. 2020;99:e20899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7373620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000020899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vohra R, Madhavan S, Sambamoorthi U. Comorbidity prevalence, healthcare utilization, and expenditures of Medicaid enrolled adults with autism spectrum disorders. Autism. 2017;21:995&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27875247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361316665222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolaidis C, Raymaker D, McDonald K, Dern S, Boisclair WC, Ashkenazy E, Baggs A. Comparison of healthcare experiences in autistic and non-autistic adults: a cross-sectional online survey facilitated by an academic-community partnership. J Gen Intern Med. 2013;28:761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23179969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-012-2262-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason D, Taylor H, Ingham B, et al. Views about primary care health checks for autistic adults: UK survey findings. BJGP Open. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3399/BJGPO.2022.0067 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/BJGPO.2022.0067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35618408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9904800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy N, Kennedy J, Kerr M, Dredge S, Brophy S. Original research: health checks for adults with intellectual disability and association with survival rates: a linked electronic records matched cohort study in Wales. UK BMJ Open. 2022;12:49441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty M, McCowan S, Shaw SCK. Autistic SPACE: a novel framework for meeting the needs of autistic people in healthcare settings. Br J Hosp Med. 2023. https://doi.org/10.12968/HMED.2023.0006 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/HMED.2023.0006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turcotte P, Shea L. Physical health needs and self-reported health status among adults with autism. Autism. 2021;25:695&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33322913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1362361320971099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>