<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37730535</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2369</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nephrology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Knowledge, attitude, and practice of patients receiving maintenance hemodialysis regarding hemodialysis and its complications: a single-center, cross-sectional study in Nanjing.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>275</StartPage><MedlinePgn>275</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12882-023-03320-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Good knowledge of and attitudes toward hemodialysis and its complications might be expected to promote good practices and improve adherence. This study investigated, the knowledge, attitude, and practice of patients receiving hemodialysis regarding hemodialysis and its complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional study enrolled patients with uremia who were receiving hemodialysis at the Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University (China) between January 9, 2023, and January 16, 2023. A questionnaire was designed that included the following dimensions: demographic/clinical information, knowledge, attitude, and practice. Correlations between knowledge, attitude, and practice scores were evaluated by Pearson correlation analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis included 493 patients (305 males, 61.87%). The average knowledge, attitude, and practice score was 19.33&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;7.07 (possible range, 0-31), 28.77&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;3.58 (possible range, 8-40), and 43.57&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.53 (possible range, 11-55) points, respectively. A higher knowledge score was associated with younger age (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), a higher education level (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), and not living alone (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), while a higher practice score was associated with a shorter history of hemodialysis (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). There were positive correlations between the knowledge and practice scores (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.220, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001) and between the attitude and practice scores (r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.453, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), although the knowledge and attitude scores were not significantly correlated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results provide important insights into the knowledge, attitudes, and practices of patients with uremia in Nanjing (China) regarding hemodialysis and its complications. These findings may facilitate education programs to improve self-care practices in patients receiving maintenance hemodialysis in Nanjing (China).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Fangfang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhuang</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongxia</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hui</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Hongyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bian</LastName><ForeName>Xueqin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China. bianxueqin@njmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ye</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Kidney Disease, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, 210000, China. 240252560@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NMUB2020046</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development Fund of Nanjing Medical University:General program</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967793</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2369</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">End-stage renal disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodialysis, surveys and questionnaires</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Uremia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37730535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-023-03320-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12882-023-03320-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agarwal R. Defining end-stage renal disease in clinical trials: a framework for adjudication. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2016;31(6):864&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfv289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeera Levin PE, Stevens RW, Bilous J, Coresh, Angel LM, De Francisco PE, De Jong, et al. Kidney disease: improving global outcomes (KDIGO) CKD work group. KDIGO 2012 clinical practice guideline for the evaluation and management of chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int Suppl. 2012;3(1):1&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrows NR, Koyama A, Pavkov ME. Reported cases of end-stage kidney disease - United States, 2000&#x2013;2019. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(11):412&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.mm7111a3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35298452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8942306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurlow JS, Joshi M, Yan G, Norris KC, Agodoa LY, Yuan CM, et al. Global epidemiology of end-stage kidney disease and disparities in kidney replacement therapy. Am J Nephrol. 2021;52(2):98&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000514550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33752206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta R, Woo K, Yi JA. Epidemiology of end-stage kidney disease. Semin Vasc Surg. 2021;34(1):71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.semvascsurg.2021.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33757639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8177747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Yang Z, Wang J, Wang HY, Su Z, Chen R, et al. Estimation of prevalence of kidney disease treated with Dialysis in China: a study of insurance Claims Data. Am J Kidney Dis. 2021;77(6):889&#x2013;97. e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2020.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan L, Zuo L. Current ESKD burden and its future trend in Beijing, China. Clin Nephrol. 2015;83(7 Suppl 1):17&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5414/CNP83S017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25725236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masud A, Costanzo EJ, Zuckerman R, Asif A. The complications of Vascular Access in Hemodialysis. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2018;44(1):57&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0037-1606180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28898900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morfin JA, Fluck RJ, Weinhandl ED, Kansal S, McCullough PA, Komenda P. Intensive hemodialysis and treatment complications and tolerability. Am J Kidney Dis. 2016;68(5S1):43&#x2013;S50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2016.05.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murdeshwar HN, Anjum F, Hemodialysis. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL) ineligible companies. Disclosure: Fatima Anjum declares no relevant financial relationships with ineligible companies. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griva K, Nandakumar M, Ng JH, Lam KFY, McBain H, Newman SP. Hemodialysis Self-management intervention Randomized Trial (HED-SMART): a practical low-intensity intervention to improve adherence and clinical markers in patients receiving hemodialysis. Am J Kidney Dis. 2018;71(3):371&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.09.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29198641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AM AA, Al-Khattabi GH. Factors influencing adherence to Hemodialysis Sessions among patients with end-stage renal disease in Makkah City. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2021;32(3):763&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1319-2442.336772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata KN, Shen JI, Nishio Y, Haneda M, Dadzie KA, Sheth NR, et al. Patient knowledge and adherence to maintenance hemodialysis: an international comparison study. Clin Exp Nephrol. 2018;22(4):947&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10157-017-1512-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29185127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saran R, Bragg-Gresham JL, Rayner HC, Goodkin DA, Keen ML, Van Dijk PC, et al. Nonadherence in hemodialysis: associations with mortality, hospitalization, and practice patterns in the DOPPS. Kidney Int. 2003;64(1):254&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1523-1755.2003.00064.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12787417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade C, Menon V, Ameen S, Kumar Praharaj S. Designing and conducting knowledge, attitude, and practice surveys in Psychiatry: practical Guidance. Indian J Psychol Med. 2020;42(5):478&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0253717620946111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7750837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghannadi S, Amouzegar A, Amiri P, Karbalaeifar R, Tahmasebinejad Z, Kazempour-Ardebili S. Evaluating the effect of knowledge, attitude, and practice on self-management in type 2 Diabetic patients on Dialysis. J Diabetes Res. 2016;2016:3730875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/3730875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27478845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4958437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spies HC, van den Berg VL, Nel M. Knowledge, attitude and practices of patients receiving maintenance haemodialysis in Bloemfontein, South Africa. South Afr J Clin Nutr. 2021;34(3):116&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16070658.2020.1751415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagarajah S, Velraja S, Arambakkam H. Knowledge, attitude, and practices of renal diets among hemodialysis patients. Biomed Biotech Res J. 2022;6(1):86&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/bbrj.bbrj_200_21</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alipur B, Hossein K, Azhiri SA, Fard AA, Nejad MK. STUDY OF NUTRITIONAL KNOWLEDGE, ATTITUDE AND PRACTICE IN PATIENTS UNDERGOING HEMODIALYSIS. Med J Tabriz Univ Med Sci. 2002;56:57&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isarannavar GS, Moni AV. Assess the knowledge and attitude of patients undergoing hemodialysis regarding their dietary management in the district hospital at Karwar (UK), Karnataka with the view to prepare dietary guide. Int J Sci Health Res. 2017;2(4):18&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pessoa NRC, Linhares FJ. Hemodialysis patients with arteriovenous fistula: knowledge, attitude and practice. Esc Anna Nery. 2015;19(1):73&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5935/1414-8145.20150010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal Q, Shareef A, Afzal A, Ashraf S, ARTERIOVENOUS FISTULA CARE:. KNOWLEDGE, ATTITUDE AND PRACTICE IN ESKD PATIENTS ON HEMODIALYSIS. Prof Med J. 2018;25:1426&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borzou SR, Rasoli M, Khalili Z, Tapak LJ. Comparison of Group discussion and teach back Selfcare Education Effects on Knowledge, attitude, and performance of Hemodialysis Patients. Nephro-Urology Online. 2020;12(3):e105938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi H, Sadeghi M, Amanpour F, Dadgari A. Influence of nutritional education on hemodialysis patients knowledge and quality of life. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2016;27(2):250&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1319-2442.178253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26997377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alikari V, Tsironi M, Matziou V, Tzavella F, Stathoulis J, Babatsikou F, et al. The impact of education on knowledge, adherence and quality of life among patients on haemodialysis. Qual Life Res. 2019;28(1):73&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-018-1989-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victoria A, Evangelos F, Sofia ZJ. Family Support, Social and demographic correlations of non-adherence among Haemodialysis Patients. Am J Nursing Sci. 2015;4(2 &#x2013; 1):60 &#x2013; 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Untas A, Thumma J, Rascle N, Rayner H, Mapes D, Lopes AA, et al. The associations of social support and other psychosocial factors with mortality and quality of life in the dialysis outcomes and practice patterns study. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2011;6(1):142&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.02340310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3022236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agustina F, Yetti K, Sukmarini L. Contributing factors to hemodialysis adherence in Aceh, Indonesia. Enfermeria Clin. 2019;29(Suppl 2).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SY, Zang XY, Liu JD, Cheng M, Shi YX, Zhao Y. Indicators and correlates of psychological disturbance in chinese patients receiving maintenance hemodialysis: a cross-sectional study. Int Urol Nephrol. 2015;47(4):679&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11255-015-0910-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25627912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerogianni S, Babatsikou F, Gerogianni G, Koutis C, Panagiotou M, Psimenou E. Social Life of Patients undergoing Haemodialysis. Intl J Caring Sci. 2016;9:122&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng MSN, Chan DNS, Cheng Q, Miaskowski C, So WKW. Association between Financial Hardship and Symptom Burden in Patients receiving maintenance Dialysis: a systematic review. Intl J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(18).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baser F, Mallaoglu M. The effect of a hemodialysis patient education program on fluid control and dietary compliance. Hemodial Int Int Symp Home Hemodial. 2019;23(3):392&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hdi.12744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali KM, Mullan J, Roodenrys S, Hassan HC, Lambert K, Lonergan M. Strategies to improve dietary, fluid, dialysis or medication adherence in patients with end stage kidney disease on dialysis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized intervention trials. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(1):e0211479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0211479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30695068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6350978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arad M, Goli R, Parizad N, Vahabzadeh D, Baghaei R. Do the patient education program and nurse-led telephone follow-up improve treatment adherence in hemodialysis patients? A randomized controlled trial. BMC Nephrol. 2021;22(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-021-02319-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8028152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>