<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37730570</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Extended postpartum intimate partner violence and its associated factors: community-based cross-sectional study design.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>501</StartPage><MedlinePgn>501</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-023-02649-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Intimate partner violence is a global problem that threatens mothers. It has multidimensional consequences but has not gained attention from scholars after childbirth.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the prevalence of extended postpartum intimate partner violence and its associated factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">A community-based cross-sectional study design was employed among 570 postpartum mothers in Arba Minch Town, Southern Ethiopia, from May 21st to June 21st, 2022. A pretested, face-to-face interviewer-administered structured questionnaire was used. Bivariable and multivariable logistic regression analyses were used. The level of statistical significance was declared at P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 with a 95% CI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, the prevalence of extended postpartum intimate partner violence was 45% (95% CI: 40.89, 49.20). Participants whose husband has no formal education (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.62; 95%CI: 1.32, 9.90) and only secondary education (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.96; 95%CI: 1.56, 5.48), husband alcohol consumption (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.73; 95%CI: 1.06, 2.80), husband dominance in decision-making (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.94; 95%CI: 1.13, 3.33), husband disappointment in the gender of the baby (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.13; 95%CI: 1.28, 3.56), previous history of intimate partner violence (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;5.71; 95%CI: 3.59, 9.07), and low social support (AOR&#x2009;=&#x2009;4.37; 95%CI: 2.53, 7.55) were significantly associated factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The prevalence of extended postpartum intimate partner violence was found to be high. Thus, increasing awareness of husbands with no formal education and having lower academic achievement, incorporating maternal social support assessment into maternity and child health care; teaching on alcohol reduction behavior and gender roles; and screening of mothers during the prenatal period should be given.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wedajo</LastName><ForeName>Lema Fikadu</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of medical and Health Sciences, Mettu University, Metu, Ethiopia. lemafika2014@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamo</LastName><ForeName>Abera Mersha</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Nursing, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Arba Minch University, Arba Minch, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alemu</LastName><ForeName>Solomon Seyife</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Midwifery, College of medical and Health Sciences, Mettu University, Metu, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mesfin</LastName><ForeName>Bezawit Afework</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, Arba Minch University, Arba Minch, Ethiopia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-based</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Extended postpartum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intimate partner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Violence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37730570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-023-02649-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-023-02649-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Violence against women prevalence estimates, 2018: global, regional and national prevalence estimates for intimate partner violence against women and global and regional prevalence estimates for non-partner sexual violence against women. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller E, McCaw B. Intimate partner violence. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(9):850&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1807166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiding M, Basile KC, Smith SG, Black MC, Mahendra RR. Intimate partner violence surveillance: Uniform definitions and recommended data elements. Version 2.0. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Understanding and addressing violence against women: intimate partner violence. In. World Health Organization; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahenge B, St&#xf6;ckl H, Abubakari A, Mbwambo J, Jahn A. Physical, sexual, emotional and economic intimate partner violence and controlling behaviors during pregnancy and postpartum among women in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(10):e0164376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0164376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27755559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5068783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lencha B, Ameya G, Baresa G, Minda Z, Ganfure G. Intimate partner violence and its associated factors among pregnant women in Bale Zone, Southeast Ethiopia: a cross-sectional study. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(5):e0214962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0214962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6494036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahey JO, Shenassa E. Understanding and meeting the needs of women in the postpartum period: the perinatal maternal health promotion model. J Midwifery Women&#x2019;s Health. 2013;58(6):613&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jmwh.12139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei N, Azadi A, Zargousi R, Sadoughi Z, Tavalaee Z, Rezayati M. Maternal health-related quality of life and its predicting factors in the postpartum period in Iran. Scientifica 2016, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Preventing intimate partner and sexual violence against women: taking action and generating evidence. World Health Organization; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal A, Ickovics J, Lewis JB, Magriples U, Kershaw TS. Postpartum intimate partner violence and health risks among young mothers in the United States: a prospective study. Matern Child Health J. 2014;18(8):1985&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10995-014-1444-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24562504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4142118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FitzPatrick KM, Brown S, Hegarty K, Mensah F, Gartland D. Physical and emotional intimate partner violence and women&#x2019;s health in the first year after childbirth: an australian pregnancy cohort study. J Interpers Violence. 2022;37(3&#x2013;4):NP2147&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260520934426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32608316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcacine KO, Abuchaim EdSV, Jardini L, Coca KP, Abr&#xe3;o ACFdV. Intimate partner violence among postpartum women: associated factors. Revista Brasileira de Enfermagem. 2018;71:1306&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0034-7167-2016-0643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29972528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amiri M, Mohammad-Alizadeh-Charandabi S, Mirghafourvand M, Farshbaf-Khalili A, Ranjbar F. Intimate partner violence during the first year after childbirth in an urban area of Iran: prevalence and its predictors. Int J Womens Health Reprod Sci. 2018;6:491&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15296/ijwhr.2018.81</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munro-Kramer ML, Scott N, Boyd CJ, Veliz PT, Murray SM, Musonda G, Lori JR. Postpartum physical intimate partner violence among women in rural Zambia. \International J Gynecol Obstet. 2018;143(2):199&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenberg K, Wobil P, Betts CL, Wiesner TF, Gold KJ. Intimate partner violence among mothers of sick newborns in Ghana. Health Care Women Int. 2016;37(5):583&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07399332.2015.1037444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25864483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson JL, Uthman C, Nichols-Hadeed C, Kruchten R, Thompson Stone J, Cerulli C. Mental health therapists&#x2019; perceived barriers to addressing intimate partner violence and suicide. Families, Systems, &amp; Health 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal SK, Hooker L, Vally H, Taft A. Partner violence and postnatal mental health: cross-sectional analysis of factors associated with depression and anxiety in new mothers. Aust J Prim Health. 2018;24(5):434&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/PY17174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30103851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojahed A, Alaidarous N, Kopp M, Pogarell A, Thiel F, Garthus-Niegel S, Hindin P, Btoush R, Brown DR, Munet-Vilaro F. Prevalence of intimate partner violence among intimate partners during the perinatal period: a narrative literature review. Front psychiatryJournal Family Violence. 20212015;12(8):61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindin P, Btoush R, Brown DR, Munet-Vilaro F: Intimate partner violence and risk for cervical cancer. Journal of family violence 2015, 30(8):1031&#x2013;1043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durevall D, Lindskog A. Intimate partner violence and HIV in ten sub-saharan african countries: what do the demographic and health surveys tell us? The Lancet Global Health. 2015;3(1):e34&#x2013;e43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(14)70343-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25539967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misch ES, Yount KM. Intimate partner violence and breastfeeding in Africa. Matern Child Health J. 2014;18(3):688&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10995-013-1294-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23807715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsedal DM, Yitayal M, Abebe Z, Tsegaye AT. Effect of intimate partner violence of women on minimum acceptable diet of children aged 6&#x2013;23 months in Ethiopia: evidence from 2016 ethiopian demographic and health survey. BMC Nutr. 2020;6(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40795-020-00354-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabarwal S, McCormick MC, Silverman JG, Subramanian S. Association between maternal intimate partner violence victimization and childhood immunization in India. J Trop Pediatr. 2012;58(2):107&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tropej/fmr052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21705763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakphong MK, von Ehrenstein OS. Intimate partner violence and childhood illnesses in Cambodia: a cross-sectional study. Arch Dis Child. 2020;105(3):223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/archdischild-2019-317663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31949033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. WHO recommendations on postnatal care of the mother and newborn. World Health Organization; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niolon PH. Control CfD, Prevention: preventing intimate partner violence across the lifespan: a technical package of programs, policies, and practices. Government Printing Office; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Ethiopian Health Sector Transformation Plan II. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirirsa DE, Desta AA, Geleta TA, Gemmechu MM, Melese GT, Abebe ST. Intimate partner violence in the postpartum period and its associated factors among women attending a postnatal clinic in Central Ethiopia. SAGE Open Medicine. 2022;10:20503121221100136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121221100136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35646358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9130815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellsberg M, Jansen HA, Heise L, Watts CH, Garcia-Moreno C, WHO Multi-country Study on Women&#x2019;s Health and Domestic Violence against Women Study Team. Intimate partner violence and women&#x2019;s physical and mental health in the WHO multi-country study on women&#x2019;s health and domestic violence: an observational study. Lancet. 2008;371(9619):1165&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60522-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye M, Hanlon C, Wondimagegn D, Alem A. Detecting postnatal common mental disorders in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: validation of the Edinburgh postnatal depression scale and Kessler scales. J Affect Disord. 2010;122(1&#x2013;2):102&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2009.06.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19615753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster J, Linnane JW, Dibley LM, Hinson JK, Starrenburg SE, Roberts JA. Measuring social support in pregnancy: can it be simple and meaningful? Birth 2000, 27(2):97&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano M, Cacciatore A, Giordano R, La Rosa B. Postpartum period: three distinct but continuous phases. J Prenatal Med. 2010;4(2):22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alene T, Atnafu A, Mekonnen ZA, Minyihun A. Acceptance of human papillomavirus vaccination and associated factors among parents of daughters in Gondar Town, Northwest Ethiopia. Cancer Manage Res. 2020;12:8519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CMAR.S275038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwaramba T, Ye JJ, Elahi C, Lunyera J, Oliveira AC, Sanches Calvo PR, de Andrade L, Vissoci JRN, Staton CA. Lifetime prevalence of intimate partner violence against women in an urban brazilian city: a cross-sectional survey. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(11):e0224204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0224204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31725729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6855440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getaneh M, Jara D, Alle A, Arora A, Tsegaye TB, Birhanu MY. Modern contraceptive use and Associated factors during extended Postpartum Period among Women who gave birth in the last 12 months at Northwest Ethiopia. Int J Gen Med. 2021;14:3313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S317649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8285232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semahegn A, Torpey K, Manu A, Assefa N, Ankomah A. Adapted tool for the assessment of domestic violence against women in a low-income country setting: a reliability analysis. Int J Women&#x2019;s Health. 2019;11:65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJWH.S181385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Putting women first: ethical and safety recommendations for research on domestic violence against women. In.: World Health Organization; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatta N, Assanangkornchai S. Patterns of domestic violence against women during pregnancy and the postpartum period in Kathmandu, Nepal. Asia-Pacific Psychiatry. 2019;11(1):e12342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/appy.12342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30474319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groves AK, Moodley D, McNaughton-Reyes L, Martin SL, Foshee V, Maman S. Prevalence, rates and correlates of intimate partner violence among south african women during pregnancy and the postpartum period. Matern Child Health J. 2015;19(3):487&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10995-014-1528-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24889116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4254902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laelago T, Belachew T, Tamrat M. Prevalence and associated factors of intimate partner violence during pregnancy among recently delivered women in public health facilities of Hossana town, Hadiya zone, southern Ethiopia. Open Access Libr J. 2014;1(07):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadhosseini E, Sahraean L, Bahrami T. Domestic abuse before, during and after pregnancy in Jahrom, Islamic Republic of Iran. EMHJ-Eastern Mediterranean Health Journal, 16 (7), 752&#x2013;758, 2010 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jobo MM. The prejudiced negative images of femininity in Wolaita proverbs. Int J Soc Cult Lang. 2016;4(1):58&#x2013;68. (Special Issue on African Cultures and Languages)).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Bapat U, More NS, Alcock G, Joshi W, Pantvaidya S, Osrin D. Intimate partner violence against women during and after pregnancy: a cross-sectional study in Mumbai slums. BMC Public Health. 2013;13(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-13-817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatta N, Assanangkornchai S, Rajbhandari I. Does husband&#x2019;s alcohol consumption increase the risk of domestic violence during the pregnancy and postpartum periods in nepalese women? BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-10021-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan YY, Rosman A, Ahmad NA, Mohamad Kasim N, Abd Razak MA, Omar M, Abdul Aziz FA, Awaluddin SM, Yusof M, Jamaluddin R. Prevalence and factors associated with intimate partner violence among postpartum women attending government primary health care clinics in Malaysia. J Family Violence. 2019;34(2):81&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-018-0014-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oseso L, Krakowiak D, Nduati R, Farquhar C, Kinuthia J, Osoti AO, Guthrie B. Past intimate Partner Violence Predicts Incident intimate partner violence during pregnancy and post-partum in pregnant women in Kisumu, Kenya. Int J Gynecol Obstet 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finnbogad&#xf3;ttir H, Dykes A-K. Increasing prevalence and incidence of domestic violence during the pregnancy and one and a half year postpartum, as well as risk factors:-a longitudinal cohort study in Southern Sweden. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KL, Lo C, Lu Y, Ho FK, Leung WC, Ip P. Intimate partner violence before pregnancy, during pregnancy, and after childbirth: a new conceptualization highlighting individual changes in violence against pregnant women over time. J Interpers Violence 2021:0886260521997451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar NK. Informed consent: past and present. Perspect Clin Res. 2013;4(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2229-3485.106372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23533975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3601698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>